{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Which is the most popular JavaScript framework?",
      "option": ["Angular", "React", "Svelet", "Vue"],
      "points": 10,
      "correctOption": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Which campany invented React?",
      "option": ["Google", "Apple", "Netflix", "Facebook"],
      "points": 10,
      "correctOption": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "What's the fondamental building block of React apps?",
      "option": ["Components", "Blocks", "Elements", "Effects"],
      "points": 10,
      "correctOption": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "What's the name of the syntax we use to describe the UI in React components?",
      "option": ["FBJ", "Babel", "JSX", "ES2015"],
      "points": 10,
      "correctOption": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "How does data flow in React app?",
      "option": [
        "From parent to childern",
        "From children to parents",
        "Both ways",
        "The developer decides"
      ],
      "points": 10,
      "correctOption": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "How to pass data into child components?",
      "option": ["State", "Props", "PropTypes", "Parameters"],
      "points": 10,
      "correctOption": 1
    },

    {
      "question": "When to use derived state?",
      "option": [
        "Whenever the state should not trigger a re-render",
        "    Whenever the state can be synchronized with an effect",
        "Whenever the state should be accessible to all components",
        "    Whenever the state can be computed from another state variable"
      ],
      "points": 10,
      "correctOption": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "What triggers a UI re-render in React?",
      "option": [
        " Running an effect",
        "Passing props",
        "Updating state",
        " Adding event listeners to DOM elements"
      ],
      "points": 10,
      "correctOption": 2
    },
    {
      "question": " When do we directly touch the DOM in React?",
      "option": [
        "When we need to listen to an event",
        "When we need to change the UI",
        "When we need to add styles",
        "Almost never"
      ],
      "points": 10,
      "correctOption": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "  In what situation do we use a callback to update state?",
      "option": [
        "When updating the state will be slow",
        "When the updated state is very data-intensive",
        "When the state update should happen faster",
        "When the new state depends on the previous state"
      ],
      "points": 10,
      "correctOption": 3
    },
    {
      "question": " If we pass a function to useState, when will that function be called?",
      "option": [
        "On each re-render",
        "Each time we update the state",
        "Only on the initial render",
        "The first time we update the state"
      ],
      "points": 10,
      "correctOption": 2
    },
    {
      "question": " Which hook to use for an API request on the component's initial render?",
      "option": ["useState", "useEffect", "useRef", "useReducer"],
      "points": 10,
      "correctOption": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Which variables should go into the useEffect dependency array?",
      "option": [
        "Usually none",
        "All our state variables",
        "All state and props referenced in the effect",
        "All variables needed for clean up"
      ],
      "points": 10,
      "correctOption": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "An effect will always run on the initial render.",
      "option": [
        "True",
        "It depends on the dependency array",
        "False",
        "In depends on the code in the effect"
      ],
      "points": 10,
      "correctOption": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "When will an effect run if it doesn't have a dependency array?",
      "option": [
        "Only when the component mounts",
        "Only when the component unmounts",
        "The first time the component re-renders",
        "Parameters"
      ],
      "points": 10,
      "correctOption": 3
    }
  ]
}
